<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David D. Hofmann</title>
    <link>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on David D. Hofmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 20:00:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daviddhofmann.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some Insights on Scaling/Standardizing</title>
      <link>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/post/2021-09-19-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 20:00:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/post/2021-09-19-scaling/</guid>
      <description>When we fit a statistical model, we usually scale our covariates to a mean of zero and standard deviation of one. But how does this actually influence the model and how does scaling change the way in which we need to interpret resulting model coefficients? Moreover, can we backtransform model coefficients from the scaled into the unscaled world? In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a detailed look at scaling and examine why we scale, how to scale, and how to backtransform a model containing scaled covariates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Sensitivity Analyses in R</title>
      <link>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/post/2021-06-27-sensitivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/post/2021-06-27-sensitivity/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever tried to conduct a sensitivity analysis of your ecological models? Usually this involves running a model repeatedly using different parameters and investigating how predictions are influenced by varying different parameters. Doing this in R can be incredibly frustrating, especially when a large number of parameters are involved. Here, I will show you a relatively painless and simple workflow that will enable you to complete such analysis with clean and short code using tibbles from the tidyverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Microsoft&#39;s MegaDetector to Detect Animals on Cameratrap Images</title>
      <link>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/post/2021-04-15-megadetector/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/post/2021-04-15-megadetector/</guid>
      <description>Camera trap studies usually deal with thousands of camera trap images that have to be organized and sorted. In this blog-post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to illustrate how you can use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s MegaDetector to automatically detect animals in camera trap images. This can be very useful to automate the identification and removal of images that do not contain any animals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevation Data in R</title>
      <link>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/post/2021-03-23-elevation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/post/2021-03-23-elevation/</guid>
      <description>Elevation data is a crucial element of many ecological studies. Unfortunately, collecting, cleaning, and stitching tiles from a digital elevation model is often tedious. Thus, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can access elevation data straight from within R. In addition, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to derive terrain features and how to use the rayshader package, a package for beautiful 3d plots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gallery</title>
      <link>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/top/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/top/gallery/</guid>
      <description>   P6161160
      P7050610
      P7070872
                                 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/search/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/search/placeholder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daviddhofmann.github.io/top/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! My name is David D. Hofmann and I am a PhD student in ecology at the University of Zurich in Switzerland. Prior to my PhD, I did a master’s degree in economics and soonafter a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in environmental sciences. The latter ultimatelly led to my current position as a PhD student. My research interests mainly include spatial data analysis, remote sensing, movement ecology, and conservation science. Together with my colleagues at Popecol, I am currently working on the African wild dog dispersal project in Botswana.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
